<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Short</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adam Short</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing how Collision Groups are set in CS:S</title>
      <link>/blog/blog/fixingcollision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/blog/fixingcollision/</guid>
      <description>Counter-Strike: Source (CS:S) was released November 1, 2004, over 15 years ago. Since its release, it did not take long before people were already pushing the game to its limits with modifications using SourceMod. In pushing the limit, though, mistakes were made and things got a bit messy. One of the biggest issues (at least that I ran into) was the Collision Groups going to hell once you changed the group for an entity (usually a client) known as the &amp;ldquo;Physics Mayhem bug&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to JavaScript</title>
      <link>/guides/guides/intro_to_javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/guides/intro_to_javascript/</guid>
      <description>Last updated August 21, 2019 @ 09:33
Quick Links  About JavaScript Hello World Assigning Variables Comparison Interpolated Strings Arrays Classes Objects Exceptions and Error Handling Var vs. Let Final Notes  About JavaScript JavaScript is weakly (loosely) typed language and is essential for developing web applications. It allows the sites to be interactive and not static like this one. JavaScript is &amp;lsquo;object-based&amp;rsquo;, although there are 7 primitives (variable types that are not objects).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guides</title>
      <link>/guides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>2019 Here is my one publication from that time I was a PhD student (even though I was an undergraduate when I did the paper):
 Towards an Empirically-Based IDE: An Analysis of Code Size and Screen Space Adam C. Short and Austin Z. Henley VL/HCC &amp;lsquo;19: IEEE Symposium on Visual Languages and Human-Centric Computing (Memphis, TN) Short paper. pdf  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>